<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Flow Stability Research Group</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/</link><description>Recent content on Flow Stability Research Group</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 13:45:06 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>New paper published: analytical irregular initial condition of the Navier-Stokes equations</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_23_new_paper_comp_condition/</link><pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 13:45:06 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_23_new_paper_comp_condition/</guid><description>Our paper is published about a three-dimensional, analytic flow example that does not fulfill the compatibility condition. Therefore, the solution is irregular at the initial time.</description></item><item><title>Conference in Athens</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_14_efmc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 13:45:06 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_14_efmc/</guid><description>From our research team, Dr. György Paál and Dr. Tamás Péter Nagy presented our latest research results in connection with miniature vortex generators and a new type of stability testing method at the European Fluid Mechanics Conference held in Athens.</description></item><item><title>Modeling the effect of surface roughness</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/fel%C3%BCleti_erdesseg_modell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/fel%C3%BCleti_erdesseg_modell/</guid><description>A key topic of fluid mechanics is that surface roughness with a height of 10-100 μm significantly affects flow losses. Irregular roughness increases the loss, but streamwise elongated riblets decrease it.</description></item><item><title>Conference in Paris</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_9_edrfcm/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 13:45:06 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_9_edrfcm/</guid><description>From our research team, Dr. Tamás Péter Nagy and András Szabó presented our latest research results on the ability of miniature vortex generators and elastic coatings to delay the laminar-turbulent transition.</description></item><item><title>Delaying laminar-turbulent transition using elastic coatings</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/elasztikus_bevonat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/elasztikus_bevonat/</guid><description>In liquids, the laminar-turbulent transition can be delayed, which can reduce the flow losses. The topic aims at more sophisticated modeling and design of elastic coating than in previous studies.</description></item><item><title>Delaying laminar-turbulent transition using Miniature Vortex Generators (MVGs).</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/mvg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/mvg/</guid><description>Vortex generators are tipically used to delay separation, thereby reducing the profile drag. Recent studies have shown both theoretically and experimentally that properly designed vortex generators can delay the laminar-turbulent transitions, and reduce the friction drag significantly.</description></item><item><title>Development of new instability investigation tools</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/energiaegyenlet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/energiaegyenlet/</guid><description>Prediction of turbulence is one of the most challenging problems in fluid mechanics, especially in a strong external disturbance environment. The motivation of this topic is that as turbulence can significantly affect flow losses and transport phenomena, prediction of it would have a lot of practical applications.</description></item><item><title>Reduced order modeling of the cavity tone</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_ureghang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_ureghang/</guid><description>Cavity tone is one of the simplest aeroacoustic configurations. The flow above a cavity creates a shear layer that is unstable and tends to oscillate. The oscillating shear layer is coupled to the cavity, which acts as a resonator.</description></item><item><title>A new Ph.D. student joins our research group</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_uj_phd_hallgato/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:45:06 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/news/2022_szept_uj_phd_hallgato/</guid><description>A new member has joined to our research group. Márton Kulcsár continues his studies with us. He will mainly work on the applicability problems of miniature vortex generators under the supervision of Dr.</description></item><item><title>Drag reduction</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/research/dragreduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 20:56:42 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/research/dragreduction/</guid><description>Instabilities in fluid flows can significantly increase unwanted losses. Thus, much more energy is needed to move a vehicle in the surrounding fluid in the presence of the instability waves.</description></item><item><title>Aeroacoustics</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/research/aeroacoustics/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/research/aeroacoustics/</guid><description>Flow oscillations play an important role in aeroacoustics. In such cases, the movement of the air is accompanied by a significant sound emission, which is sometimes desirable but can also be unwanted.</description></item><item><title>Reduced order modeling of the edge tone</title><link>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_elhang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>FlowStabilityHungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_elhang/</guid><description>The edge tone is one of the simplest aeroacoustic configurations. It consists of a plane jet opposed by a wedge. The jet oscillates with well-defined frequencies as it impinges on the wedge, which can also produce sound.</description></item></channel></rss>