<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>SSC Topics on Flow Stability Research Group</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/</link><description>Recent content in SSC Topics on Flow Stability Research Group</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 16:48:28 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Modeling the effect of surface roughness</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/fel%C3%BCleti_erdesseg_modell/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/fel%C3%BCleti_erdesseg_modell/</guid><description>A key topic of fluid mechanics is that surface roughness with a height of 10-100 μm significantly affects flow losses. Irregular roughness increases the loss, but streamwise elongated riblets decrease it.</description></item><item><title>Delaying laminar-turbulent transition using elastic coatings</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/elasztikus_bevonat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/elasztikus_bevonat/</guid><description>In liquids, the laminar-turbulent transition can be delayed, which can reduce the flow losses. The topic aims at more sophisticated modelling and design of elastic coatings than in previous studies.</description></item><item><title>Delaying laminar-turbulent transition using Miniature Vortex Generators (MVGs).</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/mvg/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/mvg/</guid><description>Vortex generators are tipically used to delay separation, thereby reducing the profile drag. Recent studies have shown both theoretically and experimentally that properly designed vortex generators can delay the laminar-turbulent transitions, and reduce the friction drag significantly.</description></item><item><title>Development of new instability investigation tools</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/energiaegyenlet/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/energiaegyenlet/</guid><description>Predicting the onset of turbulence is one of the most challenging problems in fluid mechanics, especially in a strong external disturbance environment. The motivation of this topic is that as turbulence can significantly affect flow losses and transport phenomena, prediction of its onset would have a lot of practical applications.</description></item><item><title>Reduced order modeling of the cavity tone</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_ureghang/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_ureghang/</guid><description>The cavity tone is one of the simplest aeroacoustic configurations. The flow above a cavity creates a shear layer that is unstable and tends to oscillate.</description></item><item><title>Reduced order modeling of the edge tone</title><link>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_elhang/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Dec 2019 15:44:46 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://flowstabilityhungary.github.io/en/topics/rom_elhang/</guid><description>The edge tone is one of the simplest aeroacoustic configurations. It consists of a plane jet opposite to a wedge. The jet oscillates with well-defined frequencies as it impinges the wedge, and can also produce sound.</description></item></channel></rss>